All right. So, Google Flow just got an
update and there's three points I want
to bring up to you guys. First one,
ultra subscribers get V3 fast videos
with zero credits. That means that
included in your subscription price is
unlimited V3 fast videos. So, that is
for Ultra subscribers. So, if you're
wondering what Ultra is. Most of you
have the Google AI Pro plan, which is a
$20 a month. This is the Pro. The Ultra
is the one that you get 25,000 monthly
AI credits across Flow. And that one is
$125 for the first three months and then
it's $250 a month. But now this 25,000
credits is only going to count if you're
making quality videos because fast is
going to be zero credits at this point.
So you can generate essentially
unlimited V3 fast. I'm not sure how long
that's going to last, if it's a
temporary promotion or not, but
currently this is where we are at at the
end of August 2025. And then the second
update
is that we can now generate
customize or consistent first frame
images inside of Flow with the
combination of their image generation
which uses AI and the frames to video
feature. And I'm going to show you an
example of that. And the cool thing
about the image generation for the first
frame is that you can now use a
reference image to control the quality
and the reference style of your image.
And I'm also going to show you what that
means here in a second. And then third,
it doesn't say here on this update
window, but I just saw that recently
they brought back the student discount.
If you are a college student and you
have a .edu email, you can get Google AI
Pro for free for the first year. You see
right here, are you a student? Get
Google AI Pro free for one year. So that
is the three points, the three updates I
wanted to bring you guys. This went away
in June, but it came back now almost
we're almost at the beginning of
September. So, I'm assuming they're
doing this because summer has cooled off
and now we're back to school and they're
bringing this back. So, essentially,
you're saving yourself $20 a month if
you have a edu email, if you're a
student. Now, let's go to the update
where it talks about the images. Okay,
so here I generated all these images.
Essentially, these are my first frame
images. This is where this is the point
of generating them inside of Google Flow
using the Gemini interface. So, I'll
show you how to get here. And I did make
some videos before. So, here's a I
picked one of those images to create
this right here. Let me play it for you
guys.
So, that's the point of you generating
the first image. Essentially, it's free
because even if you're being charged the
credits if you have the pro, you can
still use this image generation without
burning up your credits because you did
not generate a video yet. You're just
generating the image and Gemini gives
you the image access
for as part of your subscription price.
Here's another one that I created using
an image and a style. So, I made this
kind of neon style. Let me play this one
of these for you. I made three
generations at once. You know, when I
tell you guys just to have one output
here instead of three or four. In my
case, it's free. It's zero credits. So,
I did I went ahead and did three just
because I wanted to see which one would
be better. And number two is the best
one. Watch this one.
I really miss the old days when I could
ride this thing.
So I I generated this image as my first
frame image using a character reference
and a style reference. And this is how I
accomplished this. So to generate this,
if you want to go ahead and read this
update, it was kind of confusing.
I didn't get it until I actually started
putting into practice. So this is this
is what this says that you can do.
And I found out just by playing around
with it because I didn't understand what
they're talking about. So here you're
going to go to frames to video and then
on the plus button you click right here
on the plus. You're going to have to
generate image. Okay? You can't upload
an image because your image is already
baked. It's already done. If you upload
one you have to generate. This is the
whole point of of your first frame being
able to um use Gemini as your engine
inside of Flow. Since it's all Google,
they're giving you access already built
in in here. So now there's no image here
because we didn't generate anything yet.
This is how you generate an image. You
can do it straight from a prompt. You
can just put old man skating, but it
might just give you anything. You don't
know the reference what the character is
going to look like. You don't know what
the style is going to look like. To
control that, we would have to go ahead
and click plus on the first one. You can
generate, you can add up to three image
references for your, for example, like
if you want a red couch, there's a red
couch right here. If you want this old
man right here, this is the guy I use.
You click on that one. In this case, let
me pick um let me pick let me pick
something different that I haven't
picked yet. Okay,
so I'm going to pick this guy right
here.
That's my character reference.
And then here I'm going to if I want to
add a couch, for example, I want him
sitting on that couch. I'm gonna add
this couch right here. Got it? That's my
second. You can do up to three image
references. That's not to be confused
with style reference. Style reference is
the third, I mean the fourth button
right there. And the style is something
like this is the the GTA kind of vibe
that somebody was just saying. This is
the one that you can pick the neon
lights. You can pick a kind of a Mars
looking one. You can pick a Mad Max kind
of style. Let's go ahead with um let's
go ahead with this one here.
The kind of the Mars looking one. Okay.
So, here I'm going to put man. I'm going
just be very basic. Sits on the couch in
the middle
of
the landscape. Not even going to say
which landscape.
It it should know.
All right. This is the second or third
time I' I've played around with this.
So, this is a basic prompt not to
confuse anybody. Just keep it simple.
Man sits on the red couch in the middle
of the landscape. This is the man. This
is the couch. And this is the landscape.
Let's send it. The point of this is to
control what your first frame is going
to look like. If you have a whole movie
that takes place in that that landscape,
guess what? Every time you generate your
first frame, you're going to use that as
your reference style.
Look at that. That's the couch. That's
the man. That's the That's the That's
the place. So, every time you generate
your film, you can add that as your
reference style.
Okay, there's more. There's one, two,
three, four. I like the first one
better. And we can we can further we can
further edit this. Okay, if you don't
like it because it's too sharp or you
want to make it more cinematic.
First of all, if you like it, the simple
way to do it would just to be click use
this image right here on the bottom.
Right here on the bottom, it says use
this image. Let's go ahead and first of
all, let me let me save this image
first. So then I can show you how I
modify it later. But for now, let's say
I'm happy with this and I want to use
it. I'm going to click use this image
right here. And you're like, use it
where? Well, the whole point is to use
it as your first frame, right? So when
you hit use this image, what it does is
it's going to give you the first frame
loaded with that image. So then here
because you already have your character,
you already have your setting and you
already have your shot composition.
That's a character described through the
image. That's the setting described
through the image already. And that is a
shot composition which is a wide shot
already depicted in the image. It's
framed as a wide shot. So now the only
two last things you need to add is your
character's dialogue and your
character's action. So in this case,
character
says, and currently I received a
notification from Google. There was a
popup that said they're having issues
with audio. So if the audio doesn't
work, it's understandable because they
did notify me that there's an issue with
the audio generations today. Character
says,
just type the fe the new feature
that allows us to control
the ingredients
and style. Remember, the ingredients is
are things like the character, the
couch, if he's holding a bottle, if he's
holding a product, you can put that
product, a stock photo of that product
inside one of those three boxes you you
get, and you can just say, "This
character sitting on this couch holding
this product, and there you have a drink
commercial that you can sell.
Ingredients and style."
of your first frame
is unbelievable.
The sky is the limit. Now, so that's
what he says. Let's go ahead and just in
case put this in quotes here. It does
work a little better sometimes. And then
I'm going to put no captions
in case it wants to give me those
captions. I haven't had that happen in a
while. But so there we go, guys. We have
the first frame and now we just wrote
our our prompt and make sure this is V3
fast. And because I am currently on my
ultra plan and I have zero credits taken
out when I when I render these videos,
I'm going to pick two videos to see
which one is better. It's going to give
me two exports. So frames to video frame
is here. Let me send it
while that's cooking here. Okay, we have
the 1% going. I'm going to go ahead and
show you guys how I would edit that
image
if I wasn't happy with how it's looking.
And I'm doing that with the new update
of Gemini, which is now 2.5,
aka Nano Banana. The way you access Nano
Banana is by going to Google
AI Studio. You can just Google that and
you it will take you to this page. And
then specifically for me, I want to be
able to edit the components of the
image. So to edit the image, it's kind
of like the Google AI Studio version of
Photoshop. The way you get here is on
the left sidebar. Remember Google AI
Studio is where I went to. This is the
homepage. This is what it's going to
look like. On this left sidebar, it will
say build. You have to go through here
if you want to specifically manipulate
your elements in the photo like a
Photoshop.
So build and then here you have to go to
Pshop.
Pop here on the right.
And this is not part of V3. I mainly
teach V3 through my course, but this is
something that's because it's part of
Google. I'm just going to show you this
as a bonus so you can understand some
extra things that you can also do. If
you need help with this, you're gonna
have to poke around with it. I'm just
showing you how to access it as an
example of how you improve that first
photo, the first frame if you don't like
the way it looks. So, here in Pikshop,
I'm going to go ahead and upload an
image. And because I saved that image,
I uploaded it right here. And if you're
wondering, how do I save the image?
Remember when we were on the step before
in that interface where I showed you
four images? You have to rightclick on
the image and hit copy image. It's the
only way. There's no save image option.
You have to hit copy image and then from
there you paste it into your computer's
uh paint and then you can save it or you
can paste it into like a Canva uh
project and save it. But you have to
paste that image somewhere and then save
it. There's no rightclick save as PNG or
JPEG. doesn't work that way inside of
that interface. It's not like the
regular Gemini interface. It's the only
workar around that I found. Let's go
ahead and play this video and then we'll
hop back to this. Let's go ahead and
play the video since it's already here.
Let's play the first and then we'll do
the second one.
>> This new feature that allows us to
control the ingredients and style of
your first frame is unbelievable. The
sky is limit now. This new feature that
allow
>> messed up the typing. The sky is the
limit now. Not limit. That was my fault.
Here's the second one.
>> This new feature that allows us to
control the ingredients and style of
your first frame
>> is unbelievable. The sky is limit now.
>> All right. I'm going to do the limit.
So, I'm going to redo I'm going to use
reuse prompt right here on this little
button here next to the photo. The sky
is
the limit. Now,
I'm going to send it.
Make sure this is two. This is just for
my own use. I'm going to let that go.
I'm not going to show you guys on this
uh on this pass because I already showed
you the video. Let's focus now on how to
edit this image. Okay. So, here it says
retouch, crop, adjust, and filters.
So, I'm going to show you how to retouch
first. If you want to click anywhere in
this image and give it a prompt, you can
do so. Let's click on his head right
here.
Let's type add cowboy hat.
Add cowboy hat.
Generate. See what it looks like.
This is possible. This is nano banana.
This is the way that you can now add
elements to your photo
inside of the Google AI platform using
the build tab and then you go to pix
shop. So there you go. It's only one
option. So if you don't like it, you
have to undo
and then you can either redo it or you
can just undo and then click it again
and type it again. In this case, let's
just keep it on. And then here guys, I
think the background is a little too
crisp. It's a little too crisp for my
taste. So what I want to do now here is
go to and if feel free to play around
with the retouch. You can click here and
you say add, you know, you can add
anything. You can add a an animal,
add more mountains, add clouds. I'm not
going to do that for time sake, but
let's go to adjust now. And then here it
says blur background. This is what I
want. I'm going to click blur background
and then you can actually add another
prompt here in addition to the blur
background. It says describe the
adjustment. So I can say like add trees
as well or add more mountains, add
a car since this is this is going to be
a prompt window as well. You can type
whatever you want to see in the
background here. I'm just happy with the
blur background. So I'm going to leave
that clicked. See enhance warmer light
studio light. blur background is what I
want. And I'm going to click apply
adjustment. The blue button behind me.
So, the apply adjustment is going to
work. And then there we should have a
more cinematic look that doesn't look so
photoshopped. See how the background is
blurred? Now, if you can't see it, I'm
going to go back and try to spot the
difference because I know the screen is
kind of small and you might have a
limitation of what how much you're
seeing here. This is what it looks like
before the adjustment and this is what
it looks like after. I definitely see a
difference. The aperture is actually
shallow. That's when your camera picks
up the forefront and in the background
is blurred. This is exactly what
happened here. Let me show you another
quick adjustment that you can do.
Because this environment is so red,
let's add a warmer lighting effect and
hit apply adjustment. It should give a
more
red hue to the entire image now.
See how that worked? I actually don't
like that as much. So, I'm going to keep
it the other way.
It went too crazy with the with the red.
So, I'm just going to undo it. And then
let's see what a studio lighting would
do.
Studio lighting. Let's click on that and
hit apply. Just know guys that every
time you you hit uh an effect, it it
slightly
deteriorates the quality of the image.
It slightly it slightly makes it worse
quality.
So don't do more than five times. You
know, if you want to make your
adjustments maybe to do two at a time.
Yeah, I'm not feeling that studio
lighting either because it's not really
in the studio environment. And then you
can also do enhance details to bring
everything back to being sharp because
remember I told you every time you do a
pass,
it lowers the quality a bit more. So now
it's going to give you a higher fidelity
image. I see it here in person because
it's it's bigger for me. So it did work
out perfect here. Now it's sharp. The
quality is restored. So I always do that
at the end and see how it looks. So I'm
happy with this. Now let's see. Let's
say I want to retouch it one more time
and click here and and say
add a
stampede.
See if that would work.
Generate. I just click behind them.
It's usually good at single items when
you add a bunch of objects like that or
a bunch of character. Oh, there you go.
It worked out. I take it back. I was
going to say when you add a bunch of
elements, sometimes it doesn't really
give you uh the best results. But hey
guys, this is why we're doing this live
and figuring this out for you guys. This
just came out not too long ago, few days
ago. So, there we go. Horses all have
four legs. They look good. No double
heads. Looks nice. I can go ahead still
and adjust and do another blur
background. Let me see if it looks a
little more cinematic because the horses
are a little too sharp.
But every time you There you go. Now
it's too It's too blurry now. So I'll go
back to that. See, that's why you have
to play around with it. If I wanted the
picture to be focused on the guy,
perfect. But I kind of want to see the
horses. So let's go back. There we have
it. So here now we're going to download
image. Download image.
And in this case, you can just hit a
download button. The green button is
right behind me. If I move myself here,
I just hit that button and that's when I
downloaded the image. It went to my
folders. So, you can go ahead back to
go back to your Google Flow project
frames to video. And then you're going
to upload that image that you just
downloaded. There you go. It's slightly
bigger than the frame one. So, you can
move it around. You have some room to
play with this. And then you can do crop
and save.
And that will upload the image for you
here.
Now you have your first frame here. Now
you can put your prompt in. So I'm going
to just copy this again. Same prompt
that I wrote before.
Character says new feature that allows
us to control the ingredients and style
of the first frame is unbelievable. I'm
just gonna not say anything about the
horses. Let's see what AI does with the
horses. Okay, let's keep it at one
generation. No, let's do two just to
keep the just to keep my It's already
two. So, let's send it just to keep the
look here kind of square so everything
matches. While that's making, let's go
watch this and see what happens here. I
said I wasn't going to play it, but
since we are generating another one, why
don't we just check this one out?
>> This new feature that allows us to
control the ingredients and style of
your first frame is unbelievable. The
sky is the limit. Now,
>> it's interesting how that went back and
this one went forward. this new feature
that allows us to control the
ingredients and style of your first
frame.
>> I see this one.
>> It's quite a view from up here, isn't
it?
>> This one is completely
>> different from what I'm used to, but
change can be good.
>> I like that. He went rogue a little bit
on that one. I no idea why he said that.
>> It's quite a view from up here, isn't
it? Different from what I'm used to, but
change can be good.
>> There you go. This one's almost done.
This is the one that we tailored with
Nano Banana with the Gemini 2.5 update
using Google AI Studio to add horses.
Add a cowboy. I didn't even realize
that. Now it matches, right? Because he
has a cowboy hat. We have the horses.
Let's see what I didn't say anything
about horses. How to act how to make
sure the horses are are getting
animated. Let's just see if it's smart
enough to make them run.
>> This new feature that allows us to
control the ingredients and style of
your first frame is unbelievable. The
sky is the limit. Now
>> couch is moving. Let's see the second
one.
>> This new feature that allows us to
control the ingredients and style of
your first frame is unbelievable. The
sky is the limit. Now,
>> this new feature that allows us to
control the ingredients and style of
your first frame is unbelievable. The
sky is the limit now.
>> So, there you have it, guys. This is how
you're going to be able to use those
tools to create a tailored look for your
videos.
Have fun.